[staff] Do you still remember him?
Of course.
Who could ever forget him?
Son of a bitch! Best coach ever!
Oh, are we not allowed to curse?
Shit.
Nicole Cordoves, Philippine...!
[clears throat]
Sorry, let me try again.
Philippines!
[Nicole] He taught me to say it like that.
[MJ] I dieted intensely just to maintain
my figure before the pageant.
As in, water therapy.
May I have another glass of water?
What was he like as a pageant coach?
["Reyna" by Michelle Dee playing]
MOTHER BEAUTY
[Nicole] He's…
Strict.
That's how you do it!
You get it?
- Yes, Mother!
No absences at rehearsal
since he never misses it either.
Controlling.
[Twinkle] Let's go!
Project!
Shoulders back.
Overly competitive.
[Twinkle] Come on! [claps]
Make them feel your presence!
He made me balance all sorts of things.
Books, pillows…
[slurping]
Intimidating.
[Twinkle] Look fierce!
I said "fierce," not constipated!
[sobbing]
- [staff] Please eat first.
- No!
If he hadn't whipped me into shape,
I wouldn't have this crown today.
[Chelsea] That's Mother.
He pushes you to reach your best.
Actually, even better than the best.
[Twinkle] No!
They'll strut until their feet bleed,
all for the crown!
- Yes, Mother!
Strut!
[Carlene] Because of Mother,
I am the first Filipina
to win two national titles.
Look at my two crowns.
[MJ] I may have failed today,
but Mother always told me,
it's not about how many times I fall.
[Nicole] He is not just a coach.
He is a mother.
He mothered us.
You are a mother,
Mother!
[Twinkle] Mother Twinkle.
That's what they call me.
- Twinkle!
- [Twinkle] Huge arms.
Dear! They rushed your mother
to the hospital!
Huh?
[Twinkle] Just when I thought
I knew everything about being a mother,
you came.
Twinkle,
what will happen to your mom's ward?
You're taking over.
[Mama M] Here, hold the baby
while I take care of the guests.
[Twinkle] Can I be a mother?
[baby fussing]
[baby crying]
Hi, dear.
Let's start.
Start what, Mother?
I've been waiting for you for three hours.
Everyone from our meeting
has already left.
I'm sorry. I had no one
to leave the baby with, poor thing.
I convinced the board of Miss Uniworld
to make Mother Beauty a partner
because I believe in you!
Even if everyone else is saying
that you've lost your touch.
Oh no! What's wrong, baby?
Oh no, he threw up.
- Wait a minute. Oh no, not now.
- [baby continues crying]
At least get me a tissue!
It's okay, baby.
[Twinkle] Can I give you
everything you need?
Were you the one who called earlier?
Yes, ma'am. Here are all my things.
Let me see.
Baby, I'm just selling some stuff, okay?
Take this.
Here you go.
Madam, I don't think
this fairly covers everything.
I'm sure we can get the price higher.
- My baby is sick.
- Oh dear.
Sure, there's a lot,
but it's old and worn out.
It's not worth much, to be honest.
There are crowns and trophies there.
My pageant daughters won them overseas!
Oh, that's true, sis!
And those were big-deal pageants!
Prestigious!
I don't care. Take care of your sick baby.
Go home.
- I'll figure something out. Come on.
- But this is not enough.
Let it go. I already called backup.
[baby crying loudly]
Final answer?
- It's okay.
- Are you sure about this?
You're taking the baby to the orphanage?
I thought you'd grown attached.
I'm completely exhausted, Mama M.
I honestly don't know what to do anymore.
I'm really panicking.
[Mama M] Your mother died
at the worst possible time!
Wait, baby. I need to get dressed.
Be quiet for a second.
- [snaps]
- [baby crying]
Angelo!
- What happened?
- He swallowed a bead!
- Let's take him to the hospital!
- Spit it out!
[Twinkle] Oh my God!
Spit out the bead!
[tense music playing]
Help!
- Please help us! Help!
- [man] What is it?
- Tricycle! Please help us!
- [engine revving]
Mister! Take us to the hospital!
- [car honking]
- Taxi! Please, stop!
- Help! Mister!
- [driver] Hey!
[tense music continues]
Excuse me!
[onlookers] Oh my!
The baby!
Help!
- What happened?
- Help! The baby!
- Help the baby! Save him!
- [woman] Oh my, the baby!
- [nurse] Yes, ma'am.
- The baby.
- [whimpers]
- [woman] Oh my!
- Are you all right, ma'am?
- The baby.
[concerned gasps]
[Mama M] You're gonna make
my bangs fall off from worry!
What if you got hurt?
You just took off like that!
You almost flew with the baby!
I panicked, Mama M.
I blacked out.
Oh, God.
I would never forgive myself
if anything bad happened to Angelo.
So, what now?
Your beauty queen legs
are all scratched up.
[doctor] The baby is safe now.
- We retrieved the bead.
- Oh, thank God.
By the way, who are the baby's parents?
I am!
I'm his mother.
[doctor] I'll also get
your discharge papers ready.
I'll leave you here for now.
[Mama M] Thank you, Doctor.
[Twinkle] People always ask,
how are children made?
But me?
I want to know…
Angelo?
How does one become a mother?
[bright music playing]
You should've gotten ready
instead of painting.
- [woman] Hi, Angelo!
- Hello!
- Good morning, Mother.
- Good morning.
You'll be late again.
Shall we hang these on the wall?
Sure!
Good morning!
- [Angelo] Good morning!
- I brought breakfast for my godchild!
[Angelo] Looks yummy!
That looks like our leftovers
from last night, Ma.
Morning, Mother!
- You ate dinner with us, didn't you?
- You cooked for so many.
It would have been a waste to leave them.
We even have enough left for breakfast.
Let me make coffee first.
[Twinkle] Shameless as ever.
Good morning, sis.
Mayet, did you heat water
for Angelo's bath?
- I forgot, sis! Sorry!
- Geez!
Mother, don't blow your top!
You'd better put away
all your mess afterward.
What are you making?
We're making placards
for the rally, Mother.
Rally?
Girl, I thought this was
for the Bini concert?
Bini?
But your face looks like wasabi?
- Mother, we have a play later.
- [Bea] Marco!
Hey! If you make me late,
you're going to be our cadaver in class!
What? What's Bea saying?
Marco's taking forever in the shower.
Ma! My painting fell!
Wow!
You're getting better at this.
Let's hang it over there!
Morning, Mother.
How about this spot?
[Angelo] Yes, Ma.
There. All displayed.
[Angelo] Yay!
[Mama M gasps] Twinkle!
Come here! Hurry up!
Mama, what's wrong?
Are you having a heart attack?
Hold your breath and see for yourself.
[reporter on TV] Beauty queen
Mara De Jesus is now engaged
to the heir of Villaverde Corporation,
Anton Villaverde.
Mara happily showed off
her 24,000-carat octagon-cut
diamond engagement ring.
- Fully paid!
- It's too early for this nonsense.
[turns off TV]
She looks like an angel, Ma!
She's so beautiful!
She's not an angel, sweetie. Come on.
Time for your bath, okay?
[Angelo] Yes, Ma.
Ma'am, what makeup do you want?
Lipstick?
Eyebrows?
Maybe some blush.
You're looking a little pale.
[Mama M] Twinkle! Dear!
Mama M!
How are you? Where'd you come from?
Who's this with you?
Good day, mate!
Oh my God!
Dorothy?
I know!
Bonkers, right?
[Twinkle] Is that really you?
But you look so pretty! Do a spin!
Oh my! She's really grown!
[Twinkle] Yes!
Peppa Pig is green now.
I thought she was pink?
- You're such a joker.
- How are you?
Still the most gorgeous
and delectable Filipina in Hong Kong!
- You're now based in Hong Kong?
- Yes!
- She came from Hong Kong?
- Yes.
I was actually planning to visit you.
But Mama M said that
this is where to find you.
This is my gig for now.
You know how it is.
Pageant money isn't steady.
Most days, nada.
So this is my hustle for now.
Exactly, sis!
I came here on purpose
to let you know there are
lots of openings again
next year at Disneyland!
- Disneyland?
- Yes!
- For real?
I told you he'd love this news!
It's been his dream to go abroad!
Go for it, dear!
Dorothy will oversee everything.
I won't just oversee,
I'll run the whole process for my bestie!
Because our agency
is looking for hotel receptionists.
- Really?
- [Dorothy] Mm-hm.
But, Mama M, you know I have a kid, right?
I can't just leave Angelo like that.
What a shame.
[Dorothy] No problem! Take him with you!
[Dorothy] If you want to go to Disneyland,
you need a passport.
[Dorothy] Yes, sis, a passport!
I hope your kid has one.
Birth certificate, Form 137,
all the papers.
You have those, right? Right?
Well…
My godchild doesn't have any of that yet
because Twinkle
hasn't legally adopted him.
Too bad.
And Angelo's always dreamt
of going to Disneyland.
What a waste.
If only there was a way…
[sighs]
Don't give me this mopey crap!
Go for it, girl!
They're just papers.
[Dorothy] Get that adoption
sorted out already.
Otherwise, it'll be a waste
of a good opportunity.
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I couldn't pick you up earlier.
I had to finish a lot of work.
That's okay.
I finished all my assignments
while waiting for you.
Wow, you're really amazing.
- Of course! I take after you!
- Stay here.
Oh, please!
And you know what?
I was the only one
who got 100 in spelling today.
Wow! I'm so proud of you!
I even told my teacher
that ever since I was a baby,
you've taught me how to write.
Correct.
That's why you stand out.
You're the best!
And because of that,
I feel like giving you a reward.
Didn't you promise me for my birthday
that you'd buy me that bike?
[bell rings]
Yes, I did!
I'm already saving up for that, sweetie.
That would be yours on your birthday.
[Twinkle] Don't worry,
I won't just give you a bike.
On your birthday,
we're going to Disneyland!
[Twinkle] Would you like that?
I love you, Mama! Mwah! Mwah!
Aw, aren't you the sweetest?
One more time, just to be sure.
Tell me again what you said?
I love you, I love you, I love you!
[Angelo] Mwah!
[Mutya] Here, please read this.
You and Angelo
will have counseling sessions
together with his biological mother.
This is such a long process
to adopt my own child.
Can't I just post it on social media
and tag all of them?
[Mutya chuckles] Oh, no.
No?
So we can get started,
do you know Angelo's biological mother?
Go on, tell her.
Yes, it's…
Mara De Jesus.
[Mutya] Mara De Jesus?
The beauty queen slash model,
slash philanthropist,
slash humanitarian aid,
slash influencer,
slash Woman of the Year awardee
of In Times Magazine 2025?
Correct! With a big fat check!
That's her.
Mara.
- [man] Miss Mara!
- [reporter] Miss Mara!
Have you heard that the age restriction
for Miss Uniworld Philippines
has been lifted?
If so, will you join?
- [man] Miss Mara!
- [cameras clicking]
[Twinkle] She was my student
back at Mother Beauty
when I was still coaching beauty queens.
Thank you, everyone! Thank you! Mara has
other commitments to attend, okay?
- Thank you!
- [reporters clamoring]
- Cut it out!
- [clamoring stops]
I won't say it again!
[silence]
- [man 1 and 2] Miss Mara!
- [crowd clamoring]
[Mutya] Scandalous!
So how did her child end up with you?
Here's the thing.
Remember the last time
she joined Miss Uniworld?
Yes! That went viral!
Exactly!
Should a woman have to choose
if your ultimate dream
required a long-term commitment
that takes you away from
your future child,
which would you choose to honor,
your career
or your child?
[breathing heavily]
[Twinkle] She was
already pregnant with Angelo then.
- [man] Medic! Get a medic!
- [Mutya] OMG!
[Mila] You are pregnant?!
How can you be pregnant?
Huh?
[Twinkle] Her mother, Mila, was furious.
- [Twinkle] Then whack!
- [others gasp]
[Twinkle] She slapped Mara.
[Mutya] Mila De Jesus?
The one who was also a beauty queen?
Correct, with a big fat check!
[Twinkle] Then…
[Twinkle] Whack!
[Mutya] Who got slapped next?
[Twinkle] There was a mosquito.
I killed it so no one would get dengue.
But the next one, this one was real.
My heart jumped.
- [Twinkle] Whack!
- [others gasp]
This is your fault!
If you had watched over Mara,
she wouldn't have gotten pregnant!
[Twinkle] She slapped Mr. J.
- [whimpers]
- [Twinkle] Full swing.
Then suddenly, even I got startled.
Out of nowhere, whack!
- [Mila gasps]
- This is your fault!
She's your daughter!
She is your responsibility!
[Twinkle] Mila was about
to retaliate! But then!
- You!
- [groans]
[Twinkle] Her hand landed on my face.
Keep your mother in line!
That shook my brain.
Of course, you fought back.
Of course not.
She's rich, remember?
She could've had me
thrown in jail back then.
But I wouldn't just let it go.
Whack!
[gasps]
Why did you slap me this time?
Because you stole Prince Cedi's costume!
[Mila] When you give birth,
we're giving the baby away.
[sobbing] But, Ma, this is my baby.
[Mila] No!
[sobs]
[Mila] Mara, Mara, Mara!
Mara! Mara!
I've long wanted to have a grandchild,
and I can't count on you.
Let's just care for the baby.
- [Mama M screams]
- Don't do it! She's your mother!
You're right.
Sorry, Ma. I was just taken aback.
Ma, I don't think I can let him go.
He'll be with a good family.
[Mila] Just give him up
and live the life you're meant to have.
- [sobbing]
- [somber music playing]
Give me the baby.
Ma, please. Please.
- Please.
- Mara!
- [soft sob]
- [tragic orchestral music swells]
[Twinkle] One day,
my mother just showed up with a baby.
[sobbing]
[Twinkle] Angelo.
It turns out,
Mila gave Mara's child to her.
After my mother passed,
well,
I became Angelo's mother.
[Mutya] Unbelievable.
Like something out of a soap opera.
[Mutya] So here's the deal.
Do you still have contact with Mara?
For this to happen,
we need her signature.
[pensive music playing]
[sniffles, sobs]
[Ms. J] That long face
doesn't really suit you.
I've known about the Miss Uniworld thing
since last week.
But whenever it comes up,
I still think of him.
I wonder if he's doing okay now.
You need to focus on the future.
On your wedding with Anton.
Not on all those what-ifs.
[Ms. J] And tonight,
you'll be meeting his parents.
So fix your face.
You don't look like a winner.
[Nanette] You know what, Mara.
I really admire you.
Even with so many people
meddling in your personal lives,
you don't seem affected.
Me? I'm fed up.
So many reporters keep calling our house,
wanting interviews with Tony and me
about your wedding.
Sorry, Auntie.
I know you're private people.
Maybe just ignore it.
Just give us a grandchild soon, okay?
[Anton] Dad,
you make it sound like you don't have
a grandchild from Andy.
What are you saying?
He's adopted.
[Nanette] What your dad means is,
family by blood is different, right?
So, when is the wedding?
Next year.
[Nanette] Aren't you moving to the States?
What's the delay?
Mara and I talked,
and she's about to do something big
before we get married.
And…
I want to support her.
What is it? I wasn't informed.
I want to compete in Miss Uniworld again
before we get married.
I want to win the crown this time.
OMG!
The queen is making a comeback!
[Nanette] Well, if that's
really what you want, Mara.
Just remember,
a crown is only for a year.
A family is forever.
[Mutya] Angelo,
do you understand what's happening?
Are you able to follow what we need to do?
Yes, ma'am.
Mama Twinkle is going to adopt me
so we can go to Disneyland.
That's right.
And once Mama Twinkle adopts you,
that means he's your legal mom.
Do you have any other questions?
Who's my other Mama?
[Angelo] Do I have a Papa?
Do I have siblings?
Cousins?
A grandma and grandpa?
They've all passed away.
Sorry?
No, sweetie.
Easy on the questions, there's too many.
She has a heart condition. She could die.
In time,
we'll explain everything to you,
but for now,
let's focus on getting
your adoption papers in order.
The important thing is,
your Mama loves you very much
and will do his absolute best for you.
[gentle music playing]
Twinkle?
In the flesh.
Who let you in?
The power of the elementals.
If you get my drift.
What brings you here?
I'm here
for my son.
Sign this
so Angelo and I can leave
this godforsaken country,
the Philippines!
[paper rustles]
[tense music playing]
- [paper tears]
- [Twinkle laughs]
[laughs loudly]
That is so predictable.
I prepared another one.
Not for long.
[clicks]
- [Twinkle shrieks]
- [Ms. J laughs]
[laughter]
This is the end for you, Mara!
[maniacal laughter]
Angelo is mine!
- My child is mine!
- [Mara and Ms. J screaming]
[laughing continues]
This is wrong.
Twinkelito…
Paoros Reyes?
Diosdado Patumbong?
You've transitioned?
Yes! Just call me Ms. J.
Twinkle?
Are you
applying to be my coach?
Coach?
I'm here because I need
something from you.
I'm adopting Angelo.
What for? You already have the child.
Because of your dry burgundy hair,
we're leaving the country,
so he needs documents.
Which means I need to legally adopt him.
Which means I need your help.
Okay.
I'll help you.
- Are you sure?
- But!
Only if you agree to be my coach
for the upcoming Miss Uniworld.
[Ms. J] Mara, think this through.
What if they find out about the kid?
That would be a scandal!
I want to get the crown.
And you're the only one that can help me.
I need a strict, heartless,
merciless perfectionist
that will make me win.
Wow.
I sound terrible in your story.
I need the best.
So I need you.
And I'm also the only one
who can help you.
I gave up pageant coaching
a long time ago.
Twinkle, please.
I trust you.
[squeaking]
[Mama M] Hey! Enough!
You've been at that for forever!
Are you trying to scrub
a hole in that pan?
What exactly happened? Did Mara agree?
- [squeaks]
- [grunts]
- She agreed!
- [water running]
But she has conditions.
Oh! What conditions?
She said she'll only help
if I train her for Miss Uniworld.
Unbelievable, right?
- Wow!
- What "wow"?
A reunion!
And if it happens,
it's a comeback for both of you.
Maybe Mara just wants to prove
she deserves the crown.
And you, you'll prove
that you're still the best pageant coach.
No! No! No! That's not happening, Mama!
If I do that, it's like giving her
a chance to get closer to…
To Angelo.
To her son.
What if she takes him away from me?
Shh!
Set boundaries. Keep it professional.
- No personal matters!
- Boundaries?
Just meet at the studio.
Never here at home.
I don't like it. Absolutely not.
My God,
of all people!
Why does Mara De Jesus
have to be Angelo's real mother?
My God! Beautiful, rich, influential.
How do I compete with that?
- I'm terrified she might take him back.
- Miss Mara is his real…?
[Mama M] Mara won't do that!
[Vince] I found out a secret!
- This is insane!
- What secret?
Miss Mara De Jesus
is Angelo's real mother.
- Hey, is that true?
- It's true!
- Oh my God!
- Hey! What's that?
[whispering]
Seriously?
Share it with me.
[whispering]
I didn't hear. Again.
Who?
You're too much.
What are you whispering about?
Oh, Mayet!
You'll faint when you hear this.
What is it?
- Huh?!
- Mayet.
- Mayet, your heart.
- [all] Mayet!
[all] Mayet! Mayet!
- Mayet!
- [Twinkle] My God! What happened?
Mayet! Mayet!
Mayet!
One thousand one,
one thousand two, one thousand three.
Clear!
- What happened?
- Oh my God, sis.
- What?
- We heard some news!
- What is it?
- But you can't tell anyone.
- Tell me.
- Should I?
- Tell me!
- Mayet!
Tell me! What is it?
- I need to know!
- I'm about to!
What is it? Tell me!
- Go tell her!
- What is it?
I'm going to!
Angelo's real mother…
Angelo's real mother
is Mara De Jesus.
Angelo's real mother is Mara De Jesus?
Exactly!
It's true!
How did you find out?
Why is this my fault?
It really is my fault, Mother.
I'm sorry.
I heard you and Mama M
in the kitchen earlier.
You?
So, sis,
is it true
that Mara De Jesus
is Angelo's real mommy?
[gasps of shock]
Oh my God.
So, that means…
We're rich!
[cheering]
We're gonna be rich!
Stop it!
Quiet!
No one can know that Mara De Jesus
is Angelo's real mother!
Go ahead! Scream it
so the whole town hears you.
Should I give you the mic too?
[breathing heavily]
[whispering] No one can know
that Mara De Jesus
is Angelo's real mother.
Absolutely
no one.
Sis, not even Angelo?
Wanna tell him?
- Wanna tell Angelo? Then do it.
- I was just asking.
- Tell Angelo! Tell him.
- [mutters indistinctly]
Mess with the kid's head.
- Tell him. Go ahead.
- Sorry! Sorry.
Make the kid rebel.
Make him run away from me.
Make him reject me.
Tell him! Go ahead!
Try it! Tell Angelo.
I'll swarm your panties with red ants.
[Ria] Ouch! That hurts!
Go ahead.
I'll make sure your privates swell up.
That would hurt.
No one can know until that woman
signs the child over to me.
[kids arguing]
Son!
Is this your son?
- Yes, sir. What's the matter?
- You should talk to him!
He threw spaghetti at his classmate!
Do you see what's going on?
I knew it. Those kids are bullying my son!
I know Angelo.
He would never do anything bad.
Right, son?
Sweetie, what did Mama teach you?
Life is like one big beauty pageant.
It's not about who throws
the strongest punch,
it's about who gives the best answer!
And when your answer is right?
You always win!
Thank you for that wonderful answer!
But still, I will report this
as we do not tolerate violence
in this school.
See? He's sticking his tongue out!
That child is the spawn of a tik-tik.
- Ma.
- What happened?
- They were making fun of me.
- Why?
I said we're moving to Hong Kong
and you'll be working in Disneyland.
- And?
- They didn't believe me.
Why?
They said not only are you gay,
you're a liar too!
They're right about that one.
I really am gay.
Nothing we can do about it.
That's not the point.
I fought them
because I don't like them
calling you a liar!
I know you would never lie to me.
Right? We're going to Disneyland?
[soft music playing]
[school bell rings]
[tense music playing]
Are we going any higher?
My neck is cramping.
Ms. J?
You can drop it.
So?
I'm here because
I'm agreeing to be your coach.
Thank God.
But I have three conditions.
[Ms. J] Excuse me. We agreed on one.
You don't wanna hear it?
Then never mind.
- Bye!
- I'm going home.
What are the conditions?
First,
I resigned from my old job
so I can go full-time for you.
So you need to double my salary.
Sure.
I'll make it four times!
As your assistant,
your bodyguard, and your accountant,
that won't be possible.
Oh, it's not possible?
Then we don't have a deal.
We'll make it possible!
I'll just deduct it from Ms. J's salary.
[Twinkle] There you go.
Perfect!
See? You can manage.
Second,
you need to help with the secret adoption.
You cannot miss the counseling sessions
because it might delay
the filing of the petition.
And you need to sign.
Okay.
Third, and most important:
You can't go near Angelo.
Angelo?
So, do we have a deal?
Game!
Mara, what did we get ourselves into?
Where are we?
Twinkle?
[footsteps approaching]
- What is this?
- Twinkle!
[maniacal laughter]
Mara, a pageant coach wouldn't
pull these parlor tricks.
Twinkle looks more like
a fraternity leader.
- Be quiet!
- Ouch!
Welcome
to my multi-level intensive training camp
exclusively for queens.
Vince. Attack.
- [yells]
- [Mara and Ms. J shriek]
[laughing]
What's so funny?
[Mama M clears throat]
[Twinkle] No cell phones allowed.
You need to focus, focus, focus.
In pageants,
you are required to give your best.
Because if you are not the best,
you are just like the rest.
Got it?
I'm excited!
Just like old times!
- Our first lesson will be...
- My signature walk?
All queens nowadays already have
their own walk, right?
So what's mine?
What's the rush?
We'll get to that.
Too eager, huh?
A signature walk is learned.
It takes hard work.
You need to earn it.
Our first lesson…
- Is balance!
- [light switch clicks]
- And posture!
[Twinkle] Balance and posture.
These are the two fundamentals
of pageantry.
- Watch me!
- [light switch clicks]
["Reyna" by Michelle Dee playing]
Oh!
Ahh!
- [Mama M] Gorgeous!
- [Vince] You can't pull that off.
- [Mama M] Whoa!
- [Vince] Oh wow!
Oh! Who is he?
[Vince] Yes, yes, yes!
Here comes the turn!
[Vince and Mama M Chuckling]
Your turn.
Go, Mara!
[Ms. J] My queen is fabulous.
There! Push!
Sway that hip!
Emote!
That's my queen right there.
Killing it!
Go, Mara! [Claps]
[Ms. J] Well done!
Emote!
Too easy!
[Mama M gasps]
You think so?
Level 2!
[Mara] Seriously?
["Reyna" continues]
Oh!
Wow! Nice! [Claps]
You truly are unbeatable!
Even the goldfish is perfectly balanced!
Wow!
Fishtacular!
[Vince] Wow! [Clapping]
[Mama M] Oh!
Step up or give up?
No freaking way!
I can see you sweating!
The fish swims fast though.
[Ms. J] Mara can do this.
Go, Mara!
- Almost there, Miss Mara!
- Emote!
Careful, it might fall.
- [Mara] Can we take a break?
- No!
Mama!
[Mama M] Oh!
This is my special recipe for chop suey!
Perfect!
What is this, a cooking show?
Careful. It's hot!
Watch and learn.
You are really good.
Let her cook!
Can you do it?
Cheftastic!
- Wow!
- [clapping]
Oh, I thought it was "too easy"?
I know what you're doing, Twinkle.
I will never give in.
No freaking way!
Don't touch it, Mara. It's hot.
Go slow, okay!
It's still steaming, Mara!
[Ms. J] Don't burn your skin.
[Mama M] We'll still eat that later.
You can quit.
Just say it.
- Careful.
- Mara, be careful!
- [screams]
- [clatters]
Mara!
- Oh my God! The chop suey!
- Mara!
[laughs]
Weak.
Can we have a water break?
No freaking way!
Mother, weren't you a little
too hard on Miss Mara?
Too hard on her?
You're the one
who clipped a tamaraw's horns,
and I'm the harsh one?
And doesn't she want to win?
You're a terrifying coach.
Poor girl.
You feel sorry for her?
Feel sorry for your face.
It's been begging for a retouch.
Easy. Feisty even here?
[Ms. J] Is this it, Mara?
The sign.
Bea, where's Angelo?
Oh, he's with Marco
in the next bar an gay, Mother.
They heard there's some kind
of mini Disneyland?
What mini Disneyland?
Mini Disneyland. The fair.
Since when did they have a fair there?
I don't know.
They passed by earlier.
Marco, where's Angelo?
I don't know, Mother.
Didn't you say you were with Angelo?
I couldn't go, remember?
I went to the gym.
Pretty sure Ria went with him.
Mother! Had dinner yet?
Then why is she here?
They said you took Angelo to the fair.
Oh, I didn't go with him.
I had an online class.
Kid, let me see that tablet.
You can't take what isn't yours!
Give it back!
Excuse me.
Give it back to him!
What if I don't want to?
Let's see about that.
Bro, you picked
the wrong kid to mess with.
You'll be sorry.
Give me that!
Hand it over!
Look what you did!
Oh no!
He broke my tablet!
[Mara] Oh, I'm sorry! Please don't cry!
Please don't cry.
[crying continues]
You're starting to piss me off.
Who actually went with Angelo to the fair?
What, he went to the fair alone?
- [crying]
- [Mara makes soothing noises]
[Mara] Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Stop crying now, please.
What are you doing here?
Angelo, son, why are you crying?
What's wrong?
- [Ms. J] A jerk tried to take his tablet.
- Angelo?
You bastard!
Why are you picking on a child?
He's a kid. He can't fight back.
Face me instead. Face me.
Hey! Why are you pulling out a knife?
We don't need to go that far.
What do you want?
A cell phone?
Here, I have a cell phone.
Who else has a cell phone?
Give it to me.
Here. What else do you need? Money?
I have money.
You don't need to stab anyone.
Come on, give him some money!
Faster, Marco!
No one should bleed!
Food. Feed him. He's hungry.
What do you want?
Here, here.
- Take him home to your mom!
- I don't want that!
You don't want to?
Come back at Christmas
if you need more, okay?
- [gasps]
- Oh my!
[Angelo continues crying]
- We'll just replace your tablet, okay?
- It's Miss Mara!
- Don't cry. Okay?
- Oh my!
- Okay.
- [onlookers] It's Miss Mara!
- It's Miss Mara!
[Angelo] You're famous, right?
Cool!
My guardian angel is famous!
Marco, bring the child inside.
[Bea] Hello, Miss Mara!
- You're so beautiful in person!
- Hello.
Go inside.
What are you doing here?
Didn't I tell you
that you can't see the child?
Uh, I came here because
you didn't return our phones.
What phones?
Cell phone?
I forgot to take them out of my pocket.
Sorry. Here, Miss Mara.
- Thank you.
- Here, Ms. J.
You got your phones.
Now leave.
Get in the car, come on!
[gate slams]
[Ms. J] Tell me the truth.
Why are you even joining Miss Uniworld?
To win the crown?
Or to get close to Twinkle and the child?
You know,
joining the pageant
has always been my dream.
Not because Mama wants me to,
but because I really want it too.
I want to redeem myself.
But at the same time,
I can't get Angelo out of my mind.
Exactly.
It's making me nervous.
What if Anton finds out?
Ms. J,
when Anton and I get married,
we'll be living in the US.
That's what he wants.
This is my last chance
to get to know my son.
I've spent so many years
wondering who he is
or what he looks like.
Do you know what that feels like?
I want to hold him
just to see how it feels.
And if working with Twinkle
is the only way to do that,
then I'll do it.
- [footsteps approaching]
- [light switch clicks]
Now of all days I forget my umbrella.
[exhales loudly]
I have a change of clothes.
Twinkle?
You're late!
What's my number one rule?
On time is late, and late is unacceptable.
[Mara] I'm sorry. It's pouring outside.
Traffic was awful.
- How did you get that scar?
- [thunder rumbling]
My scar?
That's where Angelo came out
when I had him.
- Cesarean section.
- [electricity crackles]
[cell phone chimes]
[thunder rumbles]
Oh no.
There's flooding from the heavy rain.
Start warming up.
I just have to make a call.
[line ringing]
Hello, Mayet?
Have you picked up Angelo?
[Mayet] What time is it?
So he's still at school?
Sorry, sis. I got distracted.
But I'm leaving now.
Never mind. You're unbelievable.
Is it okay
if we postpone today's training?
Yeah, it's okay.
Let's just pick up Angelo.
No, it's okay. I've got this.
Don't turn down my offer.
A wise mama once said,
a mother who loves her child
will set her pride aside.
And a wise philosopher once said,
less talking, more doing!
What are we waiting for?
Here. I have the keys. I'll drive.
Hurry!
- [rain pouring]
- [thunder rumbling]
Why did you lend me a broken umbrella?
[Angelo] Mama!
- Sweetie, stay right there.
- [motorcycle engine revs]
Hey! You're so rude!
I took forever to get ready,
and you just soak me?
Hey! How dare you?!
There he is!
I'm drenched!
The rain stopped.
- Hi, Miss Mara!
- [Mara] Hi, Angelo!
Sweetie.
Are you okay?
Yes, Ma.
I actually wanted to play in the rain,
but it stopped.
Good thing it did.
[thunder rumbles]
[rain pouring]
My gosh! The weather is so crazy.
Ma, can I play in the rain?
Oh no, sweetie, don't.
You'll catch a cold. You might get sick.
- But my guardian angel is here!
- Maybe next time.
Come on, Angelo!
- Angelo!
- [Mara shrieks]
[chuckles]
[Twinkle] Control your girl!
Or I'll drown you in the gutter!
[Ms. J] Sorry, sis.
Playing in the rain is kind of our hobby.
What are you doing?
Ma, come join us!
We're in the school grounds!
Angelo!
Son! You might get sick!
No! Come on, Ma!
Join us, Ma!
- Son!
- [Mara] Catch him!
I'm glad we're doing this after all!
This is so fun!
I told you to control your girl.
Sweetie, this is so fun!
Thank goodness you thought of this.
Here's the snack you asked for!
- [Vince] Thank you so much, Mayet!
- [Mayet] That's yummy!
Hey, guys!
I brought my guardian angel with me.
My guardian angel, Miss Mara!
Miss Mara's car broke down,
so they're staying here for now.
But she won't be staying long.
She's leaving soon, right?
She still has a shoot for a movie.
Ah, yes, sorry for the trouble.
Ms. J already called to get our car fixed.
- So as soon as it's done...
- No, Miss Mara.
You can stay here
for as long as you'd like.
- Just stay here.
- Yes.
[Ria] And we have an extra bed
in our room.
- You can spend the night here.
- [Bea] And we've just made some snacks!
- Perfect timing!
- Wow!
Aren't you just the best hosts.
You too.
What a sweet gesture!
Overnight?
You're not even paying rent,
and yet you invite someone over!
You think you own this house?
- You're all shameless.
- Your towel.
[Mayet] I'll give Angelo a bath first.
Wait. I want to show
my paintings to Miss Mara.
Sure! Show me.
These are all my paintings.
[Mara] Amazing!
- You did all of these?
- [Angelo] Yes.
You're really good at painting.
Mayet, the kid needs a bath now.
Come on.
[soft music playing]
Sweetie, eat up.
Open wide.
I don't like shrimp, Ma!
I don't like shrimps either.
- [Bea] Aww, how cute!
- We're the same.
They're alike!
[gushing]
- Mayet?
- Yes, Mother?
I told you not to put shrimp
in the noodles.
- You know I'm allergic to this, right?
- [Mayet] Huh?
Since when?
You love eating the prawn heads!
I was diagnosed yesterday.
I'm allergic today.
[Angelo and Mara sneezing]
Sorry, um,
I'm allergic to scents.
- [Bea] Wow! They're so alike!
- Seriously!
[breathing heavily]
Mother? What's wrong, Mother?
[coughing]
Did you put on perfume?
I'm allergic to scents!
[coughing]
But don't you have a collection
of scented candles, Mother?
[breathing heavily]
Mara, try this on your noodles.
I don't like that.
Ah, right.
You don't like sour garnish.
Me neither!
[Marco] Wow!
Same again?
- [Mayet] Exactly the same!
- [Ria] Exactly the same!
- [bones crack]
- [groaning]
[friends, Angelo] Mother! Mother!
- Mother!
- Oh my!
Did you put a sour garnish on my noodles?
I'm allergic to sour food!
Mother! Are you okay?
There's no point hiding it.
Angelo and I have so much in common
because I'm his real...
No!
I am!
I'm Angelo's mother!
[Ms. J] Twinkle, what are you doing?
I'm only asking for a slice
of that sticky rice.
Twinkle!
Huh?
Ah, thing is,
it's better if you mix the toasted coconut
with the sticky rice.
Wanna taste it?
[cell phone ringing]
Hello, Dorothy?
[Dorothy] Twinkle!
You got accepted in Hong Kong!
They also said you could bring your son!
- Congrats!
- Huh?
Son…
I got accepted in Hong Kong!
- Yay! I'm going with you, Mama!
- [cheering]
I got accepted in Hong Kong!
We're going to Disneyland!
Yes!
[Twinkle] We're leaving!
You should leave too!
[chuckles]
We're leaving for Hong Kong!
[Twinkle] Yes!
You should leave! 'Cause we are!
[Mara] I know I have to let go,
but why do I feel this way?
TWINKLE: ON OUR WAY TO A NEW CHAPTER
IN HONG KONG! THANK YOU, LORD!
[sobbing]
[lawyer] Miss De Jesus,
this is Atty. Esteban.
He's going to be our witness today.
And before we proceed,
I just want to make sure that
we are on the same page.
Yes, page 2, right?
There, page 2.
[lawyer] Miss, I'm talking to Mara.
Um,
if you sign this paper,
it means you give up all rights, duties,
and connection to the child.
You willingly give custody
of the child to someone else.
Are you sure about this?
Mara.
Oh, Twinkle.
I'm so glad you made it.
- Um, I got you your usual.
- I don't drink anymore.
But we're celebrating.
What are we celebrating?
What's the occasion?
Well, I'm glad you're here.
I've had something on my mind all day.
I know only you can answer it.
But what is the essence of motherhood?
What?
I know you have all
the pageant-worthy answers!
What is the essence of...
The essence of motherhood
is not about biology.
It's an act of radical, selfless love.
It's a choice to nurture, to guide,
to empower another human being
to become the best version of themselves.
And often,
it requires sacrificing
a piece of yourself.
And I
thank you!
I nailed that!
It's my turn to ask.
Okay, Miss Mara De Jesus,
this is the moment.
Okay.
The question standing between
you and the crown is this.
So, listen up, yo.
[Mara chuckles]
Mara.
Every crown demands a sacrifice.
If the price of your ultimate goal
is walking away from the person
that you are meant to protect,
then what does that say about
the queen you aspire to be?
It's been a long night.
Deal with it tomorrow.
Let's practice some other time.
Thank you for that question.
It is implied…
That walking away
is an act of selfishness,
but I believe that this true sacrifice
is an act of profound love.
I, too, walked away from someone
who needed me most.
Not for the crown,
but because I wasn't strong enough then.
The queen I aspire to be is not perfect,
but one who is honest.
Thank you.
What's up with you?
I thought we were celebrating.
This is too dramatic.
Why are we here?
Well,
I just wanted to make it up to you.
I have good news for you, Twinkle.
I signed the adoption papers.
For real?
Oh my God!
Let's have a toast!
[glasses clink]
[Twinkle] Hello, Mutya.
Mara has signed the adoption papers.
Is there any update?
[Mutya] I can drop by this week
so Angelo can prepare his written consent.
After that, we can file the petition.
Thank God.
Thank you.
[Angelo] Thank you, Mama!
We brought Miss Mara on the field trip!
[bright music playing]
[photographer] Excuse me.
All the mommies, gather 'round.
Let's take a group picture.
Twinkle, why don't you join?
No, thanks.
[photographer]
Here we go, all the mommies!
- [photographer] Okay.
- [Mara] Sir!
Hang on.
Come on, Twinkle. Join them!
Why?
He's Angelo's mom.
[photographer] Come on, Mommy!
Okay.
Let's squeeze in.
And pose.
- Smile!
- Smile, Mommies!
Get closer!
Excuse me.
What's with these lame poses?
You look like miserable mothers!
Okay, project. Chin up!
Chest out!
Everybody say: Okurr!
- Okurr!
- [photographer] Nice.
Twinkle! They're mommies.
[photographer] Okay.
- All right. And… smile!
- [camera clicks]
- [photographer] Yeah, nice.
- [mouths] Thank you.
- Okay, pose. Pose, Mommies!
- [camera clicks]
- [photographer] That's it.
Angelo, can I see your paintbrush?
Is this still good?
Ma, I need more water.
Okay, let me fill your cup.
Angelo,
next time we meet,
I'll buy you some new paintbrushes, okay?
So you'll have new ones to use.
No need, Miss Mara.
This is my favorite.
I color better with this one.
What about you?
Do you have a favorite object?
I do.
It's a remembrance
of the most important person
in the whole world.
It's the only thing he left behind.
That's why I take good care of it.
He left?
Something like that.
I let him go.
But it's okay,
because we met each other again.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I really want to make it up to him.
I want to make things right, Angelo.
[soft music playing]
[Twinkle] Sweetie!
Time to fly a kite!
Come on, get that done.
Wow!
That's beautiful!
- Is it abstract?
- [chuckles]
This one's me.
And this is you.
This is you, Miss Mara.
Oh, sorry.
It's okay.
You wanna play?
[chuckles]
- You wanna join in too?
- [chuckles]
[upbeat music playing]
[Angelo laughing]
Pull it, sweetie.
It's so high!
So high!
Wow, Angelo!
Your kite is flying so high!
- Mm!
- Come on, let's fly a kite too.
Thank you, Mama.
Thank you, Miss Mara.
Ma, can Miss Mara come to my birthday?
Uh…
Of course, if she's not busy.
Oh! Oh!
Thank you, Twinkle.
[soft laugh]
[Twinkle] Oh, look.
[Twinkle] We're done
with the games and challenges.
Honestly, I have to say, you're good.
I can see how determined you are to win.
But who are you, really?
People need to know who you are
and why you should win.
Okay. So, how do we do it?
You've been pestering me
about your signature walk.
As your coach,
I can help you polish it.
But the idea has to come from you,
what your signature walk really is.
[Mara] I don't have a signature walk.
I don't even know how to tell my story.
I gave birth, but I wasn't
really a mother per se.
And now, I'm about to become a wife.
So to be honest with you,
I don't even know who I really am anymore.
What about you?
If you were the candidate,
how would you do it?
I'm not the candidate. You are.
I know.
But I need to understand
what you're looking for.
So, show me?
[gentle music playing]
[Angelo cooing softly]
[gentle music continues]
What do you call that walk?
That's the Mama walk.
Can that be my signature walk?
[Twinkle] Mother, I can't shake
off these negative feelings.
I want to be more open toward Mara,
but whenever she shows interest in Angelo,
and I see them getting close,
I get annoyed.
Is that wrong?
It's normal.
It's natural to feel threatened by Mara
since she's Angelo's biological mother.
But now, she's signed the adoption papers.
So don't worry about it anymore.
I don't know. I have a bad feeling.
[Mama M] What's the matter?
- Mister?
- Yes?
Where's the red bike?
It's gone. I already sold it.
Why did you sell it?
My son looks at it every day.
He was expecting it as his birthday gift.
Didn't I tell you to reserve it?
You've been reserving it for six months.
But no down payment.
Someone came here to buy it,
so I sold it to them.
My goodness.
- What now? The bike's gone!
- It's fine, we'll just look elsewhere.
No, the price is double everywhere else.
And that red bike,
Angelo really wanted that one.
I can't believe this guy!
[singing] ♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
- ♪ Happy birthday ♪
- ♪ Happy birthda...  ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday to-o-o ♪
♪ You, baby! ♪
[chuckles]
Happy birthday, my son!
[cheering and clapping]
Blow! Blow out the candle.
- [blows]
- [cheering and clapping]
Can we open the gifts now?
Uh, yeah! Sure, go ahead, son.
[Vince] Yes, gifts!
- Okay.
- That one.
Let's do the big one!
It's Mother's big surprise!
- Shall we open it, Angelo?
- It's huge, right?
Okay, let's do it together...
In three, two, one!
Hey!
[boy] Just a helmet?
Where's the bike?
Isn't it nice?
Helmet?
Yup, sweetie. This is what's trending now.
You wear the helmet,
and the bike goes on your head.
[awkward chuckle]
Sorry, sweetie.
Helmet first, okay?
My baby…
But I'll get it for you later.
[boys laughing]
- Hey!
- He got a stupid helmet!
[Twinkle] Hey, hey, hey!
[sobbing]
Son…
It's really nice, though.
Don't cry.
Try it on.
This helmet's important too.
Son…
[bicycle bell rings]
[whimsical music playing]
[Mara] I see you
post about this all the time.
So I thought maybe this is
what you'd want for your birthday.
This is my dream bike!
[clapping]
[softly] I thought we had a deal.
How dare you do this to me?
Get out.
[Twinkle] Get out of my house!
Carry your bike with you.
Get out of my house!
Get out!
[bicycle bell rings]
[screaming]
- [Angelo] Ma!
- [screaming stops]
Yes, what is this?
[screaming]
What a cool bike!
And it's red!
Perfect for you, sweetie!
Right? Say yes!
It's amazing!
[awkward chuckle]
Sorry again, son, okay?
But happy birthday anyway.
I love you so much, Mama!
You are so sweet.
- Say it again, please...
- Happy birthday, Angelo!
Thank you, Miss Mara.
You saved my birthday.
- Aww.
Welcome!
[boy] Come on, Angelo!
Let's try your new bike.
[Mama M laughs] Don't go
on the street, okay?
- [Mara] Be careful!
- [Mama M] Stay in the yard!
Angelo, the hel...
Son, put on the helmet!
- [Mama M] Oh, the food!
- [Mayet] Oh yeah.
Son, the helmet!
[indistinct chatter]
[washing dishes]
Let me help you with that.
I'm thinking,
what if next year, for Angelo's birthday,
we go to Japan?
Or maybe Paris?
What other countries do you want to visit?
Nah, it's okay.
Too expensive.
And we're leaving soon, right?
We're moving to Hong Kong.
Ah, right. I'll visit you there.
Tomorrow, you're locked in
for Miss Uniworld.
And the petition will start moving.
I'm aware of that. And?
We're done.
Twinkle, is this about the bike?
I honestly didn't know
you were planning to buy that for Angelo.
Your training is over.
So there's no reason for us
to see each other anymore.
And don't show up for Angelo either.
Do you understand?
What if I still want to get to know him?
You can't deny the fact that
I'm still part of his life.
I've grown to love that child too.
If you really love that child,
leave us alone.
You'll only make things harder for Angelo
when we leave if you keep sticking around.
Think about him for once.
[water running]
[footsteps retreating]
Miss Mara!
Are you leaving already?
Yeah.
Happy birthday again, Angelo.
I just want to give you something.
Thank you. It's beautiful.
Where are you really going?
Miss Uniworld will start soon.
Mama trained you, right?
I'm sure you're going to win.
Be a good boy, Angelo.
You're acting weird.
It feels like you're saying goodbye.
It's just going to take a while
before we see each other again.
That's too bad.
You won't get to see me
learn how to ride a bike.
[soft music playing]
Can you wait for me?
I'll be the one to teach you
how to ride a bike.
Sure!
And after Miss Uniworld,
I'll teach you how to skate,
play soccer, swim...
Anything you want to learn,
I'll teach you.
Wow, really?
Just wait for me, okay?
And when I come back,
I won't ever leave again.
Promise.
Promise?
[sniffles]
[Mara] Promise.
[sobs, sniffles]
[pageant music beating]
- [Angelo] Miss Mara!
- [cheering]
- Her gown is stunning!
- Go, Miss Mara!
- [cheering]
- [Angelo] Go, Miss Mara!
- [pageant host] Live at the Big Dome.
- [Angelo] Miss Mara!
- This is Miss Uniworld Philippines 2025!
- Finally!
- [cheering]
[upbeat music playing]
Miss Mara!
[upbeat music continues]
[cheering]
You're so beautiful, Miss Mara!
[upbeat music continues]
[Angelo] Miss Mara!
[cheering]
Ma, why did you do that?
We're watching!
TV is bad for your body!
It'll weaken your lungs,
and you'll cough up blood.
- [gasping]
- TB?
Mother, that's a different thing.
It's still TB.
Neri, take this out.
Put it in storage.
- Seriously, Mother?
- How are we supposed to watch the pageant?
[Vince] Mother, come on, no to censorship!
- Yeah.
- We'll just watch on our phones, then.
- Come on.
- Your phone.
Why won't it connect?
No Wi-Fi either.
I cut it off to save money.
- Mother!
- This is ridiculous.
Why didn't you follow Ria's example?
She boycotted Miss Uniworld.
She boycotted because she had a date.
Mother, the whole Philippines
is waiting to see
if Miss Mara will finally win the crown.
- That's right!
- Mother, we can't miss this!
No watching, end of story!
Our snacks are here for our viewing party!
Oh!
Where'd the TV go?
Ma, I have to watch!
I want to cheer for Miss Mara!
[Twinkle] Angelo!
Where are you...?
Angelo!
Get back here. Where are you going?
[soft music playing]
[Angelo] Go, Guardian Angel Miss Mara!
- [Angelo exhales excitedly]
- [vendor] Oh!
["Tala" instrumental playing]
[vendor] There she is. Wow!
- Angelo!
- Wow!
I've been looking for you.
You've been right here.
What are you doing here?
Watching!
Come on, let's go home!
Come...
[people scream]
Come on! Angelo,
I'm going to get mad at you!
[people scream and cheer]
Ange...
- You're making me angry!
- [people scream]
I'm watching!
You can't. I told you
not to watch that show!
Angelo, I need you to stop right now.
[people cheering]
I'm getting angry!
- No! Come...
- I'm watching!
Let's go home!
[host] The first queen to secure her spot
in the final three is…
Miss Albay!
[cheering]
- Oh my!
- This is it!
Didn't I say no one should watch?
That's enough!
What are you afraid of?
Isn't the petition about to start?
And don't you want to see the result
of all your hard work? Sit down!
[host] Our second queen to make this cut
representing…
[cheering]
Representing the city of love,
it's Miss Iloilo!
[screams] I swear I'll protest
if Miss Mara doesn't make it
to the top three!
[excited chatter]
And now, for the final coveted spot,
the last queen to make it
to our top three…
[excited murmuring]
From a city that has been synonymous
with a new era of public service…
[deafening cheers on TV]
…the last queen standing is…
[cheering on TV continues]
…Miss Pasig!
- [cheering]
- ["Tala" by Bryan Chong playing]
Miss Mara!
- [cheering continues]
- ["Tala" continues]
Mara!
[woman] Go, Mara!
- [host] Ladies and gentlemen!
- Here she comes!
Let's give a big round of applause
to your official Final 3.
They are just one step away
from the crown.
Oh my God!
You will really be the problem
if she faints again!
All right, Miss Pasig.
Please come forward.
[cheering]
Let's go, Mara!
Good evening, Miss Pasig.
Are you ready for your question?
Yes.
All right, here we go.
What do you think is the biggest problem
young people are facing today?
Would you like me to repeat
the question, Miss Pasig?
No.
I'd like to take this moment
to answer a question from ten years ago.
[host] Miss Pasig, I'm not sure
you're allowed to do that.
Is it okay?
All right, Miss Pasig.
Thank you.
[Mara] The question was,
if I were to become a mother,
would I prioritize
my dreams over my child?
My answer then,
and my truth is…
Yes.
[Mara] I would.
Because...
Because I wasn't ready.
Because I wasn't fit to be a mother.
I was 18, and I had big dreams.
They say that the person
that's hardest to forgive
is the version of yourself
that didn't know better.
To my family,
and to Anton…
And to everyone who has stood by me,
you deserve the truth from me.
Ten years ago,
I gave birth to a beautiful baby boy.
And his name is Angelo.
[Mara] I...
I abandoned him.
I gave him to the best mother
that he could ever have.
My coach,
Twinkle.
Who I'm very, very grateful for.
[sobbing]
Shut that thing off.
Where's the remote?
Is she my real mom?
[sobbing continues]
That's right.
She's your mother.
Why didn't you tell me that
she was my mother?
Wait, let me explain.
[both sobbing]
- [Mama M shushes]
- [sobbing continues]
For so many years,
I really wish I could've
done things differently.
[Mara] But now…
I'm finally ready to accept my truth.
I'm a mother.
And I'm proud to share that to everyone.
Come on!
- Ma?
- No!
[Nanette] Let's go!
[audience cheering, clapping]
We love you, Mara!
Go, Mara!
[soft music playing]
Sweetie…
I'm really sorry.
Is that why she came here?
Is that why she bought me the bike?
Because she's my real mom?
Are you mad at her?
Is that why you didn't want
to tell me she's my real mom?
I just don't want to lose you.
Why would you lose me, Ma?
I'm so scared.
I got scared thinking what might happen.
Sweetie,
are you mad at me?
I'm still a little annoyed
because you lied to me.
[soft music playing]
Do you
want Mayet to stay with you tonight
instead of me?
I can't sleep if you're not beside me.
I will never leave your side.
That's my promise.
[sobbing]
[soft music continues]
This is the written consent
that we talked about.
You do understand that
your Mama Twinkle is adopting you,
don't you?
Okay, so, here.
On this paper,
just write everything you feel.
Whether you agree or not.
Whatever you want to say,
just put it there.
You love your Mama Twinkle, don't you?
Okay.
[soft music playing]
Does he really have to do this?
Since Angelo is now ten years old,
he has the right to choose.
[Mutya] It's important
that the consent comes from him
if he wants you to adopt him.
I AM ANGELO REYES. THE MOM I WANT IS…
[Angelo sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
Angelo, sweetie.
If this is hard for you,
you don't have to force yourself, okay?
We can wait a little longer, okay?
[soft music continues]
[cell phone chimes, buzzes]
[Mutya] Excuse me.
Um,
Mara filed a petition
to retract her signature.
So what happens now?
We'll review Mara's case again
and see if she can prove
that she's ready to be Angelo's mother.
What, she's taking him?
[Mutya] Not yet.
But we explained this
to you before, right?
That if the biological mother
changes her mind,
we will do everything possible
to reunite them.
No. Get out. Leave.
Leave.
- Twinkle.
- Ma!
Calm down.
Calm down?
You're taking my child from me,
and you want me to calm down?
She can't take Angelo from me.
Mara can't take my son.
I'll take him far away.
You can't do that.
You can be charged with kidnapping.
Kidnapping? I'm his mother. He's my child.
Do you hear what you're saying?
You can't take my child!
Please leave.
Leave!
[Vince] Hey, it's a long weekend.
Everyone in the house went out of town.
When will it be our turn?
I have an idea. Let's go to the beach.
I'm in!
[Angelo] Ma, where are we going?
Twinkle, you know this is wrong.
Don't let your emotions take over.
Let's all have dinner first,
so you can calm down?
Yes. I cooked dinner for us.
Come back inside!
- Come back upstairs.
- Let's talk things over.
- Come on, Twinkle.
- Mother, where are you going?
Hail me a taxi, please.
Twinkle.
What is this?
Why did you bring guards with you?
You threatened to run away with Angelo.
I can't allow that to happen, Twinkle.
You really think I'll hand my son
over to you just like that?
[Mutya] I'm sorry.
We wouldn't be here if you'd stayed calm.
Now, we need to place him
in a temporary home.
You can't take my son away from me.
Twinkle, calm down.
You're scaring the child.
Calm down? With what you're doing?!
With all these guards with you?!
Everything we're doing
is for Angelo's safety.
We want to make sure he's okay
while we review the petition.
Are you implying
he wouldn't be safe with me?
Huh?
You are messing with our lives.
I'll never part with my child.
Leave us alone.
- Come on, Angelo.
- [man] We're taking the child.
- Let's talk about this.
- [Twinkle] Leave us alone!
- [Twinkle] Back off!
- Let go!
- Stay out of this!
You are making a big mistake!
Angelo is Twinkle's son!
Leave them alone!
[man] Go after them! Go!
[Bea] That's our house!
[Marco] You leave!
- Ma! Don't give me to them!
- [door slams shut]
- [Angelo crying]
- No.
No, sweetie. You're staying with me.
[Mama M] Twinkle?
Twinkle, open the door!
You might regret this.
- Open the door!
- [knocking]
- Twinkle?
- [man] Open the door!
- [doorknob rattling]
- [Angelo continues crying]
[Mama M] Open up!
- Go away!
- [Mama M] Twinkle, open the door!
No one comes in!
Go away!
- Open the door! For God's sake.
- Go away! No one comes in!
- For God's sake.
- [Angelo keeps sobbing]
- [Mama M] You're scaring the kid.
- [man] Please open the door.
[man] Please open the door.
[Mama M] I'll handle this.
[Mama M] Let's all calm down.
Go away!
[Mama M] Please have pity on the child.
- [Mama M] Calm down, please.
- I will not give you to them.
- [glass shatters]
- [Angelo shrieks]
What is happening?!
- [door slams]
- [man] There.
- Go ahead, come closer!
- Twinkle, don't!
Come closer! I dare you!
- Ma!
- No one's taking my child.
You're scaring Angelo.
Ma!
- [Mutya] The kid is scared.
- [Angelo continues crying]
[breathing heavily]
[knife clatters]
- Get him!
- [Mama M] Be careful!
[Mama M] Goodness!
- [Mama M] Just a second!
- [Twinkle] Angelo!
- [Twinkle] Give me my son!
- [Angelo crying]
- Ma!
- He's my son!
- [Angelo] I don't want to go!
- [Twinkle] Let him go!
- He's my son!
- [Mama M] You're hurting him!
- [Angelo grunting]
- [Twinkle] Angelo!
Angelo! Wait!
- Come here. Come here.
- [Twinkle] Enough!
You're hurting him. Enough!
Enough. Okay, I'll let him go!
I'll let him go.
Enough.
Angelo!
[both crying]
Take him.
Take him. Okay, I'll cooperate.
Ma!
You said you wouldn't give me to them.
Are you lying to me again?
No, no.
You have to go
so you won't get hurt, Angelo.
I don't want to, Mama!
It'll just be for a while.
I'll come for you right away.
- I'll come for you! I'll fix this!
- I don't want to, Mama!
Angelo!
[Mama M] Twinkle! Twinkle! Angelo fell!
[somber music playing]
[inaudible]
[whimpering]
Ma'am, just to confirm.
Reyes is the last name, correct?
- Yes.
- Okay.
How's my son?
Ma'am, I'll update you as soon as I can,
but rest assured that the doctor
is doing everything he can.
[Mara] Twinkle!
Where's Angelo?
Mutya told me what happened.
Twinkle.
Where is he?
What happened to my son?
What happened?
You destroyed our lives.
Now Angelo is in danger
because you were selfish.
If you'd just handed him over
to the social workers,
then we wouldn't be here...
Who gave Angelo away to hide him?
You did it to protect your image
and your precious crown.
My only mistake was reconnecting with you.
All I needed was your signature.
I'm sorry, Twinkle.
I changed my mind.
I gave up the crown
because I realized that all these years,
I wanted to win not
for the title or for myself,
but for Angelo.
I thought maybe this was my opportunity
to make up for all my mistakes.
Wow.
What do you think he is?
Something that you can just
leave at the baggage counter?
You left him because he was too heavy?
Because he was embarrassing to carry?
You left him because
he was going to get in the way
of what you want to do?
And then what?
You come back after ten years
because you're done with everything else?
Because now, you are ready?
You abandoned a person, Mara.
Not an object.
Not a thing.
A life.
[Mara] I never denied that I left him.
Yes, you did!
And I know that was wrong. I accept that.
My life was a mess back then, Twinkle.
You know that.
I didn't know what to do.
Cut the crap, Mara.
I think about him every single day.
You only thought about him!
You think it's enough that
you thought about him?
Motherhood isn't just about thinking.
It's about doing.
I still gave birth to Angelo.
I'm his real mother.
You only carried him for nine months.
But I've been taking care of him
for ten years, every day.
I will never give birth
because I'm not a woman.
But I am a mother.
I am a mother, Mara!
I am his mother.
I'm his mother because he chose me.
He chose me
the moment he spoke his very first word.
"Mama."
He called me Mama.
What makes you a mother?
Did you endure anything?
Are you hurting?
Do you worry so much
when he's not with you?
You don't know how scared I get
when he is not well.
All the saints
I call on when he gets sick.
Have you ever begged for money
just to meet his needs?
Have you ever been humiliated because you
couldn't pay back the money you borrowed?
- You win! You're the one who sacrificed!
- For his field trip?
That's right!
I did sacrifice!
Could you sell a part of your body
just to extend his life?
I could
because I'm his mother.
But I'm his mother too!
I want to do all of that for him too!
All I'm asking for is a chance.
Of the two of us, you were the one
given the first chance.
But you didn't want it, remember?
The moment they cut the cord between you,
you ended your motherhood
because you didn't want him.
And from that moment,
his heart was connected to mine.
Angelo and I share one life, Mara.
Angelo is my whole world.
[sobbing]
Mara…
I'm begging you.
Please, don't take him away from me.
[both sobbing]
Please, Mara.
[doctor] Excuse me,
I'm really sorry to interrupt.
The child needs a blood transfusion.
We're having difficulty
because he's O-negative.
- If by any chance, one of you...
- I'm O-negative, Doc.
I'm the mother.
Please let me save my child.
[doctor] All right.
This way, please.
Excuse me.
[morose music playing]
[bead clatters]
[morose music continues]
[Twinkle] I thought
I could give him everything.
But in the end,
I still couldn't prove that
I'm Angelo's mother.
Don't doubt yourself as a mother.
[Mama M] You have been a good mother.
I am a witness to it.
[Twinkle] But they won't see that.
[Mama M] You're Angelo's mother.
Nothing can erase that.
But we have to accept
that Mara is also his mother.
Don't take that away from her.
- [wailing]
- [morose music continues]
- [monitor beeping]
[Twinkle] I love my son so much, Mara.
All I ever wanted was what's best for him.
I don't want him confused or hurt
just because we are fighting over him.
I'll step back.
I'll walk away.
I only ask one thing of you.
Please don't erase me from his life.
Please don't let him forget
that I am his mother too.
Shall we eat?
What's your favorite restaurant?
Mama!
[Anton] I'll just get the car.
See? I knew you wouldn't lie.
Let's go home.
Sweetie, Mara and I talked.
You made up?
[Angelo] Yay!
Since we made up,
we've decided that…
I won't continue
with the adoption anymore.
Mama?
I want you two
to spend some time together.
So you can get to know each other better.
Isn't that great? You get two moms.
She's your mom, I'm your mom.
Don't you like that?
[Mara] Angelo?
You'll stay with us for now, okay?
[sobs] Mama,
I don't want to.
I want to be with you.
Let's go home to our house.
You're the only mom I want.
I'm not going away.
I'm always right here.
I'll be right here.
I don't want that, Mama!
[Angelo] I don't want that!
[Twinkle] There's no way.
Mama has work in Hong Kong.
Remember, I got hired there?
So I have to go.
I'll go with you.
Please don't leave me!
Don't you want me anymore?
Don't you love me anymore?
[Twinkle] I do!
I'm doing this because I love you.
I love you so, so much.
[sobbing continues]
Take care...
[Angelo crying]
[Angelo] I want to be with you!
We're leaving now.
I want to be with you!
We're leaving. Get in, okay?
[Twinkle] Where's the car?
[Angelo] I want to be with you!
[Mara] Angelo, let's go.
[Twinkle] Let's go, get in.
- I want to be with you!
- Come on, sweetie.
[Twinkle] Get in the car.
[Angelo] I want to be with you!
Time to go.
- Angelo.
- Get in the car.
Mama!
[Twinkle] Bye!
- Angelo, let's go.
- [Angelo] Mama!
- Please, sweetheart. Let go now.
- Come on. Don't be stubborn.
Mama, I want to be with you!
Mama!
Bye.
[Angelo] I don't want to!
Mama, I want to be with you!
- [Twinkle] It's okay, son.
- [Angelo wailing]
Mama! [Sobs]
- Mama!
- Bye.
[mouths] I love you.
[emotional music playing]
Mama!
[Angelo keeps sobbing] Ma!
Angelo, stop crying.
- Mama!
- Hush now.
[whimpers]
[whimsical music playing]
[whimsical music continues]
Project.
Shoulders back.
Make them feel your joy.
Janine, your lipstick.
Jaylo, fix your collar, please.
Everyone, don't forget to smile.
- Yes, Twinkle!
[claps]
[Twinkle] What does it truly mean
to be a mother?
Is it when you give birth?
Or is it when you raise the child?
It was here, in Hong Kong,
that I finally understood,
being a mother isn't about
gender, distance,
or blood.
Being a mother is about the heart.
They may be away from each other.
- But the love endures.
- [mouths] Mama!
[mouths] Angelo!
[Twinkle] Because a mother's love
is for life.
[both chuckle]
I'm surprised!
- When did you get here?
- Just now.
He wanted to see you right away.
School's done, Ma.
I can spend my vacation with you now!
- [Mara chuckles]
- Stay here with me, sweetheart.
I won't return you
to your mommy anymore, okay?
- [Mara] I heard that!
- Just stay here.
What's that?
Your electricity bill?
[chuckles]
Be our godmother.
I don't want to be a godmother.
I want to be a flower girl!
[Twinkle and Mara chuckle]
I love you, Mama.
I missed you so much!
["Tala" by Bryan Chong playing]
Music to my ears!
Tell me again, please!
I love you, Mama!
I love you too!
I love you! I love you!
I missed you!
["Tala" continues]
I love you!
Kiss! Kiss!
[laughs]
- ["Tala" continues]
- [fireworks exploding]
[Twinkle] Look, baby, so many colors!
[laughs fondly]
Give me a kiss!
[happy laugh]
["Tala" continues]
[fireworks continue]
[Twinkle] So, Angelo, my son,
no matter how far apart we are,
I'm still your mom, okay?
Because you're always right here,
inside my heart.
["Tala" continues]
[camera clicks]
[song fades]
["Tala" by Bryan Chong playing]